A racing second hand, a shooting comet!
عقرب دقائق مسرِع، مُذنّب ساقط
Mystery-solving logic will moisten hearts dried by modern society!
تبلل الاستنتاجات المفككة للغموض القلوب التي جفّفها المجتمع الحديث
Today's the marvelous movie world!
ندخل اليوم عالم الأفلام المذهل
A crime occurs in the beast's shadow!
تقع جريمة في ظلّ وحش
He sees the single truth for what it is,
يرى الحقيقة الواحدة
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
يحمل مظهر طفل، لكنّ عقله عقل بالغ
His name? Detective Conan!
!اسمه المتحرّي كونان
The Giant Monster Gomera Murder Case
جريمة قتل الوحش العملاق غوميرا
Cut!
!اقطع
Ok!
!حسناً
Totally cool!
!رائع
It's the real Gomera!
!إنّه غوميرا الحقيقيّ
He truly is incredible!
!مذهل بالفعل
He looks so strong!
يبدو قويّاً جدّاً
It's been a while, Agasa!
مضى وقت طويل يا آغاسا
Oh, Mikami-kun!
!ميكامي-كن
Are these the ones who wanted to watch?
أهم من أرادوا المشاهدة؟
Yes.
أجل
Who's he?
من هذا الرجل؟
This is Director Mikami-kun, my friend and creator of Gomera!
إنّه المخرج ميكامي-كن، صديقي ومُبتكر غوميرا
Movie Director - Daisuke Mikami
ميكامي دايسكي مخرج أفلام
Nice to meet ya, kids!
مرحباً بكم يا أطفال
Say, would you like to see Gomera close up?
هل تريدون رؤية غوميرا عن قرب؟
Can we?!
أيمكننا؟
Yeah, it's break time for a while.
أجل، سنأخذ استراحة لفترة. يمكنكم خلال ذلك
Yay!
!رائع
These buildings are tiny!
هذه البنايات صغيرة
Hey, look at that!
!انظر هناك
Gomera's back is open!
!ظهر غوميرا مفتوح
A person was born from Gomera!
!وُلِد شخص من غوميرا
That's just a suit. They film it to make it look like
إنّها مجرد بذلة، وينتجون العمل بحيث يبدو
the monster is rampaging throughout this miniature city.
كما لو أنّ الوحش يثور في المدينة المصغّرة
These buildings sure are well-made...
...هذه البنايات مصنوعه بإتقان
Keep your filthy hands off, you brats!
!أنتم أيّها الأطفال
Wreck the set and
أداتشي ريوتا فنّي
Art - Ryota Adachi
!لا تلمسوها بأيديكم القذرة
you'll have heck to pay!
!ستقعون في مشكلة إن أفسدتم المسرح
Director! Do something about these kids!
!حضرة المخرج! تصرّف مع هؤلاء الأطفال
Now, now...
...هوّن عليك
Would you like me
هل تريدون أن أعتني بهم؟
Gomera Actor - Shugo Matsui
ماتسوي شوغو ممثل غوميرا
I don't have any scenes
فلا مشاهد لدينا حتّى الظهيرة
I appreciate it, Matsui-kun.
شكراً يا ماتسوي-كن
He's a nice guy!
إنّه شخص لطيف
Gomera is on kids' sides!
غوميرا في جانب الأطفال
Gomera always rampages because of bad adults, after all!
يثور غوميرا بسبب البالغين السيّئين دوماً في الأصل
And it's Emela the fairy who
وإيميلا الجنّية هي من يُخمد
Actress - Tomomi Sakaguchi
ساكاغوتشي تومومي ممثلة
quiets Gomera's rage, children!
ثورة غوميرا يا صغار
Emela? The ring fairy who comes out only when there's trouble?!
إيميلا؟ جنّية الخاتم التي تخرج عندما تكون هناك مشكلة فقط؟
That's right!
أجل
Yeah, right! Emela's this tiny!
مستحيل! إيميلا صغيرة بهذا الحجم
She looks just like her.
إنّها تبدو مثلها
But isn't she a little old?
لكن أليست كبيرة السنّ نوعاً ما؟
Hush, you!
اصمت
This is a nice staff you have.
لديك طاقم جيّد
Yes. They all love Gomera,
أجل، كلّهم يحبّون غوميرا
and they're like a family that's worked with Gomera for ten years.
وهم كعائلة عملت على غوميرا لعشرة أعوام
That will end this year.
سينتهي ذلك هذا العام
Monster movies are puerile.
أفلام الوحوش طفوليّة
Movie Producer - Osamu Kamei
كامي أوسامو منتج أفلام
Their time is over.
ولّى عصرها
Worn-out music and tedious direction.
موسيقى مبتذلة ونهج متكرر
Over-expensive sets and special effects.
مسرح باهظ جدّاً وتأثيرات خاصة
The fairy that was 14 when she debuted is now 24.
الجنّية التي كانت في الرابعة عشر عند ظهورها الأوّل أصبحت في الرابعة والعشرين
It's time to end this.
وقت إسدال ستار الختام
Ah, yes. I hear yesterday's rush film is done.
بالمناسبة، يبدو أنّ التسجيل المبدئي للفيلم قد انتهى
Go watch it in the screening room.
اذهبوا لمشاهدته في غرفة العرض
You're not going to watch?
لن تشاهده؟
No. Say, want to grab a bite? There's still the matter to discuss.
كلا. ما رأيك أن ترافقيني للأكل يا تومومي-كن؟ فلدينا ذاك الموضوع لمناقشته
No. I'll pass.
كلا، سأمتنع
What matter to discuss?
أيّ موضوع؟
It's about his next movie.
عن فيلمه التالي
He asked me to be the leading role as a policewoman.
طلب مني لعب دور الشرطيّة البطلة
How can he blame people and then ask something like that?!
كيف يلوم الناس ثمّ يطلب شيئاً كذاك؟
What's to complain about? At least you got some work.
لمَ تتذمرين؟ لديك عمل ينتظرك على الأقل
We're left out in the cold. Right, Macchan?
نحن في العراء، صحيح يا ماتشان؟
No, he asked me to be the villain...
...كلا، طلب مني أن ألعب دور الشخصية الشريرة
So it's just me?
ماذا؟ أنا فحسب إذاً؟
Whatever. Let's go check out the majestic Gomera.
لا يهمّ، لنذهب لمشاهدة غوميرا العظيم في غرفة العرض
Alright, Matsui-kun. The kids are all yours.
الأطفال في رعايتك يا ماتسوي-كن إذاً
Storeroom ♪1
المخزن رقم 1
Awesome! Look at all these monsters!
!مذهل! انظروا لكلّ هذه الوحوش
They're all the ones that Gomera beat!
!كلّها غلبها غوميرا
Hey!
أنت
Sorry! I didn't think you'd be that surprised!
آسف، لم أعتقد أن تتفاجئي هكذا
What's with that hand?
ما تلك اليد؟
It's Gomera's hand. We use it in close-up shots.
إنّها يد غوميرا، نستعملها عند اللقطات المقربة
There's also a remote-controlled face. Wanna see it?
يوجد وجه يُتحكّم به عن بعد أيضاً، أتريدون رؤيته؟
Yeah!
!أجل
Just a sec while I get it!
انتظروا، سأذهب لجلبه
Alright!
!حسناً
Are Gomera movies really going to end? They're so good...
هل ستنتهي أفلام غوميرا حقاً؟ إنّها مسلية جداً
He did say it cost lots of money...
قال أنّها تكلف الكثير من المال
It must be the food costs! Gomera is big!
لا بدّ أنه مال الطعام! فغوميرا كبير الحجم
What simpletons.
يا للبسطاء
Matsui-san!
!ماتسوي-سان
What happened to your leg?!
ما حلّ بساقك؟
It's Gomera!
!إ-إنّه غوميرا
Gomera?!
غوميرا؟
He was in here! And he stabbed me with a knife!
!كان في هذه الغرفة، وطعنني بسكّين
Where is he now?!
أين ذهب؟
He ran out that door!
هرب من ذاك الباب
Hey, wait! Kids!
!انتظروا! أيّها الأطفال
What is this place?
ما هذا المكان؟
You can see the studio...
يمكننا رؤية الاستوديو
Oh? There's someone there!
ماذا؟ يوجد شخص
Isn't he that producer?
أليس المنتج؟
Matsui-kun?
ماتسوي-كن؟
Hey, now!
مهلك
Conan-kun!
!كونان-كن
Hold on!
!انتظر
Too late he's dead!
مات
Footprints?! He escaped through that door!
آثار أقدام؟ هرب من ذاك الباب
Hey! Conan!
!كونان
Not you too!
!أنتم أيضاً
Did you see Gomera?!
أرأيتِ غوميرا؟
Right there. I just ran into him--
ذاك هو، ارتطمت به للتوّ
Wait! Was that Matsui-san?
لحظة! أكان ذلك ماتسوي-سان؟
Huh?
ماذا؟
Gomera's not here.
غوميرا ليس موجوداً
That can't be! There's no place to hide up here!
مستحيل، لا مكان يختبئ فيه هنا
Maybe he flew off?
لعلّه طار
Genta-kun. Gomera can't fly.
غينتا-كن، لا يستطيع غوميرا الطيران
It's on the ground!
سقط على الأرض
Darn! A suicide?!
تبّاً! انتحار؟
It's empty! That's impossible!
!إنّه فارغ! مستحيل
Pardon my asking, but where were you at around 11:30 a.m.?
اعذرني على السؤال، لكن أين كنت وقت وقوع الجريمة عند الحادية عشر والنصف صباحاً؟
I was on the 1st floor of the studio,
كنتُ في الطابق الأوّل للاستوديو
doing the final continuity checks alone.
أقوم بالمراجعات الاستمرارية الأخيرة بمفردي
So no one can vouch for you?
لم يكن هناك من يشهد لك إذاً؟
No...
صحيح
You're really sweating a lot.
أنت تتعرّق بشدة
Yes, I tend to sweat quite a bit.
أجل، أنا كثير العرق بطبيعتي
When you entered this storeroom, the killer was in here,
عندما دخلت المخزن، كان القاتل موجوداً
already in the Gomera costume?
وفي بذلة غوميرا بالفعل، صحيح؟
Yes...
أجل
Is he all right?!
أهو بخير؟
I gave him emergency treatment, but he needs to get to a hospital.
أعطيته علاجاً أوليّاً، لكن يجب أخذه لمشفى
He couldn't have killed him with that leg...
يستحيل أنّه ارتكب الجريمة بحالة ساقه
When the incident occurred, why where you here?
لمَ كنتِ هنا يا ساكاغوتشي-سان عندما وقعت الجريمة؟
I wanted Producer Kamei to see the rush of the final Gomera movie.
أردتُ أن يرى المنتج كامي التسجيل المبدئي لآخر أفلام غوميرا
It was really well done, so...
...كان مصوّراً بدقّة، لذا
Rush?
التسجيل المبدئي؟
Unedited film that was just recorded.
فيلم غير محرّر انتهى تصويره للتوّ
To think something like this would happen...
من كان ليظن أنّ هذا سيحصل
Say, Tomomi-san. You saw the back of the person in the suit, right?
أخبريني يا تومومي-سان، رأيتِ ظهر الشخص في البذلة، أليس كذلك؟
Yes, but I'm not sure who it was. But the way they ran...
...أجل، لكنّي لا أدري من كان. أسلوب ركضه مع ذلك
The way they ran?
أسلوب ركضه؟
Yes. They had a hard time running.
أجل، بدا أنّه يعاني من الركض
Like they weren't used to wearing it...
كما لو أنّه ليس معتاداً على ارتدائه
But of course. That would be the case for everyone but Matsui-kun.
بالطبع، سيكون ذلك حال الجميع باستثناء ماتسوي-كن
In other words, everyone but you three was in the screening room.
أي أنّ الجميع باستثناء ماتسوي-سان وساكاغوتشي-سان والمخرج ميكامي كانوا في غرفة العرض
That's right. I watched the rush too.
أجل، شاهدتُ التسجيل المبدئي بدوري
Who are you?
من أنت؟
Agasa! The genius inventor who lives next door to Shinichi-kun!
!آغاسا! المخترع العبقريّ الذي يعيش بجوار شينتشي-كن
Oh! I've heard about you!
!سمعتُ بك
You're always making oddball inventions!
تخترع أشياء غريبة دوماً
Why, you...
...أنت
Now, now!
مهلك
So was the entire staff really in the screening room?
أكان الطاقم بأسرهم في غرفة العرض حقّاً؟
She's the only one that left.
كانت الوحيدة التي غادرت
Wait, there was another who snuck out...
...لحظة، كان هناك آخرٌ خرج خلسة
Who was it?!
من هو؟
I think it was--
...أظنّه
I told you, I don't know how this paint got here!
!أخبرتكم، لا أدري كيف وصل هذا الطلاء هنا
It was him!
!ذاك الشخص
Why would I put paint in the middle of the set
لمَ أضع طلاءً في منتصف المسرح
when the taping was gonna be this afternoon?!
ولدينا تصوير في الظهيرة؟
Yeah, I snuck out.
أجل، خرجت
I noticed something on the set when I saw the rush.
انتبهتُ لشيء في المسرح عندما رأيتُ التسجيل المبدئي
Don't tell me you suspect me?
لا تشكّون بي، صحيح؟
and return to the screening room after running up the stairs.
ثمّ العودة لغرفة العرض بعد صعود الأدراج
Who put this paint here anyway?
من وضع هذا الطلاء هنا بأيّ حال؟
You did.
كان أنت
Don't you remember? You left it after the morning rehearsal.
تركته هناك بعد بروفة الصباح، هل نسيت؟
Oh, yeah! I completely forgot!
!صحيح! نسيت تماماً
Really, now!
...يا إلهي
Say, why didn't Matsui-san watch the rush?
لمَ لم يشاهد ماتسوي-سان التسجيل المبدئي؟
Don't ask me. All he said was that he didn't wanna watch.
لا أدري، قال أنّه لم يرد المشاهدة وحسب
Don't say that. He's one of the ones who wanted to quit Gomera...
لا تقل ذلك، فهو أحد من أرادوا ترك غوميرا
Matsui-san was?
ماتسوي-سان؟
Yes. I hear he often vented to the producer
أجل، يبدو أنّه كان يتذمّر للمنتج كثيراً
about being sick of Gomera and wanting to do normal roles.
سئم من دور غوميرا وأراد تمثيل أدوار طبيعية
It doesn't make sense. Where did the killer disappear to?
الأمر ليس منطقياً، أين اختفى القاتل؟
We followed the footsteps around the corner and up the stairs...
تبعنا آثار الأقدام عند الزاوية وصعدنا الأدراج
Hey, Conan-kun. Let's make a grave for Gomera.
كونان-كن، لنصنع قبراً لغوميرا
And then through that door to the roof...
ثمّ خرجنا من ذاك الباب للسطح
Come on, Conan-kun! His grave!
كونان-كن! قبراً له
Shut up! This isn't the time for that!
!اصمتي! ليس هذا وقته
Don't be getting mad like Gomera!
!لا تغضب مثل غوميرا
Like Gomera?
مثل غوميرا؟
Look at this! There's no tail mark on the steps!
انظر هنا! لا أثر ذيل له على الأدراج
That's proof that Gomera went up the steps angry!
هذا دليل على أنّ غوميرا صعد الأدراج غاضباً
Because his tail sticks up when he gets mad!
فهو يرفع ذيله عندما يغضب
Wait a minute! Could it be?!
...لحظة! أيمكن
Hey!
ا-انتظر
What's the deal, Conan?!
!ما-ما الخطب يا كونان؟
What do you see?
ما الذي تراه؟
What is it?
ماذا هناك؟
Come on, Conan!
!كونان
Conan-kun!
كونان-كن
Alright! I figured out the trick!
حسناً، عرفت الحيلة
Studio A
الاستوديو أ
Why won't you let us inside?!
!لمَ لا تسمحون لنا بالدخول؟
This is no playground for kids!
لا يمكنكم، ليس مكاناً للهو الأطفال
That way!
!من هنا
Yeah!
أجل
Yikes, there's one here too.
يوجد آخرون هنا أيضاً
Say...
...صحيح
Storeroom ♪1
المخزن رقم 1
Hey, you!
!أنتم
We forgot something!
!نسينا شيئاً
What are you all doing here?
ماذا تفعلون هنا؟
Oh, Conan-kun!
كونان-كن
We're about to take Matsui-kun to the hospital.
سنأخذ ماتسوي-كن للمشفى
It looks like he won't be able to play Gomera with that leg.
يبدو أنّه لن يستطيع أداء دور غوميرا لفترة بحال ساقه
Forget Gomera, he can't even play a person...
انسوا غوميرا، لا يمكنه أداء ...دور بشريّ حتى
So? Have you solved the case?
إذاً؟ أحللت القضيّة؟
No, I still don't know who did it.
كلا، لم أجد الفاعل بعد
Why did the killer attack Matsui-san in this storeroom?
لمَ هاجم ماتسوي-سان في هذا المخزن؟
Maybe the killer came to get the knife but was spotted by Matsui-san?
،ربما لأنّه أتى لأخذ السكّين لكن رآه ماتسوي-سان؟
Movie props can't kill people...
أدوات الأفلام لا تقتل الناس
Wait a minute! In that case, only that person can be the killer!
لحظة، في هذه الحالة لا يمكن !أن يكون القاتل سوى ذاك الشخص
What's wrong, Shinichi?
ما الخطب يا شينتشي؟
Can't find my sleep gun...
...لا أجد ساعتي المخدّرة
Professor! What do you say to--
...أيّها البروفسور! ما رأيك أن
Inspector. We're going to take Matsui-kun to the hospital.
حضرة المفتّش، سنأخذ ماتسوي-كن للمشفى
Alright.
حسناً
Not so fast!
!تمهلوا
The one responsible is in this very room!
!المجرم موجود في هذه الغرفة
Come again?!
ماذا؟
Hey! Just move your lips to what I say!
!حرّك شفتيك تزامناً مع ما سأقوله فحسب
Oh, come on! Let me have some glory too!
أين المشكلة؟ دعني أستمتع ببعض المجد بدوري
Alright, Agasa-san. If you know who did it, then please explain
إذاً يا آغاسا-سان، هلّا شرحت بما أنّك تعرف هويّة المجرم
how the killer disappeared from the roof.
كيف اختفى من السطح؟
Special effects!
!تأثيرات خاصة
You know those holographs?
تعرفون تلك الصور المجسّمة
I bet the killer was one of them the whole time!
!لا بدّ أن القاتل كان كذلك طوال الوقت
Right?
صحيح؟
What?! I ran into the killer in the hall, and even saw them escape!
ما الذي تقوله؟! ارتطمتُ بالقاتل !في الرواق، ورأيته يهرب فوق ذلك
Oh, uh, forget what I said! The truth is--
...كلا، حسناً... انسوا ما قلتُه! الحقيقة
It was a trick.
!كانت حيلة
An extremely simple one, at that.
وبغاية البساطة إضافةً لذلك
Tomomi-san and the children only saw the killer
رأت تومومي-سان والأطفال القاتل
until he or she turned the corner!
حتّى استدار في الرواق فحسب
There's no telling if the killer went up the stairs or not!
لا جزم بصعوده للجدران من عدمه بعدها
But there were footprints on the stairs.
لكن كانت هناك آثار أقدام على الأدراج
Yes...
...صـ-صحيح
Hey! Follow my voice!
!طابق صوتي فحسب
Right...
...حسناً
The killer placed the footprints on the stairs in advance!
وضع القاتل آثار الأقدام !على الأدراج سلفاً
Hardly anyone goes onto the roof.
يكاد لا يذهب أحد للسطح
It wouldn't be strange for everyone to overlook that stairway!
لن يكون غريباً ألا ينتبه أحد لذاك الدرج
Gomera's legs were probably the only parts used to make them.
اُستعملت أقدام غوميرا وحدها لترك الآثار غالباً
As proof of this, there is a tail mark in the hall but not on the stairs.
،ودليل ذلك هو وجود أثر ذيل في الرواق لكن ليس على الأدراج
The killer quickly removed the suit in front of the stairs,
خلع القاتل البذلة سريعاً أمام الأدراج
went down in the opposite direction, entered a room,
نزل في الاتّجاه المعاكس ودخل غرفةً
lit the suit on fire, and dropped it to the ground.
أضرم النار في البذلة ثم رماها على الأرض
Oh!
!هكذا إذاً
Oh, uh...
...لا شيء
But would they be able to make the footprints in advance
لكن هل سيتمكن من وضع آثار أقدام سلفاً
without knowing the color the paint on the set would be?
دون معرفة ما سيكون لون الطلاء على المسرح؟
Right, Adachi-san?
صحيح يا أداتشي-سان؟
Yeah, I just happened to put that paint there before the incident.
أجل، صادف أن وضعتُ ذاك الطلاء قبل الحادثة فحسب
Hey, now, that doesn't hold up...
كلامك متناقض
It's only natural it doesn't.
هذا طبيعيّ
Because Tomomi-san and Adachi-san are lying to cover for the killer!
فتومومي-سان وأداتشي-سان يكذبان !للتغطية على القاتل
Lying?!
يكذبان؟
That paint was placed there by the killer...
كان القاتل من وضع الطلاء عند المسرح
...to use for the footprint trick!
لاستعماله في حيلة آثار الأقدام
So these two know who the killer is?!
!أي يعرفان هويّة القاتل؟
Adachi-san probably only followed Tomomi-san's lead,
جارى أداتشي-سان ما قالته تومومي-سان فحسب غالباً
but she should know!
لكن يُفترض أنّها تعرف
She probably saw the killer when she bumped into him in the hallway.
رأت القاتل عندما ارتطمت به في الرواق على الأرجح
So who exactly is the killer?
من القاتل إذاً؟
The killer was among the four who weren't in the screening room
،القاتل بين الذين لم يكونوا في غرفة العرض المخرج ميكامي وماتسوي-سان
or who left the screening room at some point.
كما بين من غادروها في فترةٍ ما، تومومي-سان وأداتشي-سان، أحد هؤلاء الأربعة
Adachi-san was only gone for four or five minutes. Not enough time.
،غاب أداتشي-سان لأربع أو خمس دقائق فقط فلم يمتلك وقتاً كافياً
Tomomi-san saw the killer with the children; she's innocent too.
رأت تومومي-سان القاتل مع الأطفال، فهي بريئة أيضاً
That leaves Director Mikami and Matsui-san.
تبقّى المخرج ميكامي وماتسوي-سان فحسب
Hey now, Matsui-san is seriously injured,
مهلك، ماتسوي-سان مصاب إصابة بليغة
and Mikami-kun is my best friend!
!وميكامي-كن صديقي العزيز
And therefore this comes as a shock!
...ولذا سيشكّل هذا صدمةً
Yes! The killer is--
...أجل، القاتل هو
Hey!
اسمع
What're you doing, Conan-kun?
ما الذي تفعله يا كونان-كن؟
You're bothering me! Shoo!
!أنتم تضايقونني! ابتعدوا
Bothering you? Shoo?
نضايقك؟ نبتعد؟
Oh, just a noisy fly! Shoo!
!كلا، مجرد ذبابات مزعجة! ابتعدوا
So, who is the killer?
إذاً، من هو القاتل؟
The killer is you, Matsui-san!
!القاتل هو ماتسوي-سان، أنت
Get real! He couldn't escape in that suit with his injury!
أحمق! لم يكن يستطيع الهرب !في تلك البذلة الثقيلة بإصابته
Assuming he really acquired that injury before the murder.
بافتراض أنّه أُصيب قبل الجريمة حقّاً
You're saying his injury was--
...أتقصد أنّ تلك الإصابة
Yes. After the murder, he dropped the suit,
أجل، أسقط البذلة بعد ارتكاب الجريمة
returned to the storeroom, and stabbed himself with another knife
ورجع للمخزن وطعن نفسه بسكّين أخرى
to deceive us!
!لخداعنا
But the children saw his injury before the murder!
لكن رأى الأطفال إصابته قبل وقوع الجريمة
That was probably fake blood.
كان دماً مزيّفاً غالباً
This is a movie set; it would be easy to come by.
هذا مسرح تصوير، ستجده بسهولة
But after they saw his injury, they followed Gomera out to the studio!
لكن الأطفال لحقوا بغوميرا للاستوديو بعدما رأوا إصابته
There's only one way to the studio from the storeroom.
يوجد طريق واحد فقط من المخزن للاستوديو
Where exactly did Matsui-san pass ahead of them?
أين تجاوزهم ماتسوي-سان بالضبط؟
The studio is right next to the hallway door.
الاستوديو بجوار باب الرواق مباشرةً
He probably entered once the children left.
دخله بعد مغادرة الأطفال غالباً
He then donned the suit and murdered Producer Kamei.
ارتدى البذلة بعدها، وقتل المنتج كامي
This trick would need witnesses to follow the paint footprints.
تحتاج هذه الحيلة شهوداً للحاق بآثار الأقدام
I see. So he chose these children who couldn't follow as quickly.
فهمت، لذا اختار الأطفال باعتبار أنّهم بطيئون
Children are bundles of curiosity; tell them not to go and they'll go.
،الأطفال كتلة من الفضول أخبرهم ألّا يذهبوا وسيذهبون
The suit was lit on fire to destroy sweat traces inside it.
أحرق البذلة كي يمحو آثار العرق داخلها
What proof is there that Matsui-san did it?
ما دليل أنّ ماتسوي-سان كان الفاعل؟
The knife he used to stab himself is in the storeroom prop box.
السكّين التي استعملها لطعن نفسه موجودة في صندوق معدّات التصوير في المخزن
It was probably the only place to hide it;
كان ذلك المكان الوحيد لإخفائها غالباً
he couldn't walk after stabbing his leg.
فلم يستطع المشي بعد طعن ساقه
There's one more thing-- the shirt he's wearing!
!ودليل آخر، القميص الذي يرتديه
His shirt?
قميصه؟
The killer ran off at full speed with the suit still on.
ركض القاتل بأقصى سرعته وهو يرتدي البذلة
The shirt would naturally be soaked with sweat!
من الطبيعيّ أن يكون القميص مليئاً بالعرق
But his shirt has no sweat stains...
لكن لا بقع عرق على قميصه
Of course not. Because he changed it.
بالطبع لا، فقد غيّره
He changed it?!
غيّره؟
Conan-kun can prove this!
يمكن لكونان-كن إثبات ذلك
Here I am!
!ها أنا
Remember when Ayumi-chan spilled juice on your shirt?
أتذكر عندما سكبت أيومي-تشان عصيراً على قميصك؟
But that's weird. There's no stain here.
لكن هذا غريب، لا بقعة هنا
Where did you change clothes?
أين غيّرت قميصك؟
I thought you couldn't move with your stabbed leg?
ظننت أنّك لم تستطع الحركة بإصابة ساقك
Are you sure you're not mistaken, little boy?
أأنت متأكد أنّك لم تخطئ يا ولد؟
Maybe the juice was spilled on the floor instead?
لعلّ العصير سُكب على الأرض وليس القميص؟
But I really--
...لكنّي رأيت
Are you really sure? Try hard to remember!
!أأنت متأكد حقّاً؟ تذكّر جيّداً
Please! Little boy!
!أرجوك يا ولد
It's over, Tomomi-chan.
يكفي يا تومومي-تشان
He's right. I was really sweaty, so I changed shirts.
إنّه محق، كنتُ متعرقاً بشدّة فغيّرت قميصي
The shirt is inside my bag.
وضعته داخل حقيبتي
Alright! Check it at once!
حسناً، تفقدوها فوراً
Why would you kill Producer Kamei?
لمَ؟ لمَ قتلت المنتج كامي؟
Didn't he give you work in his next movie?
ألم يعطك دوراً في فيلمه القادم؟
That had never entered my mind; Gomera was all I thought about.
،لم يكن ذلك في بالي منذ البداية كان غوميرا كلّ ما فكرتُ به فحسب
But weren't you the one who wanted to quit Gomera the most?!
!لكن ألم تكن أكثر من أراد ترك غوميرا؟
That's something that Producer Kamei made up.
ذاك أمرٌ اختلقه المنتج كامي
I thought it was strange how everyone encouraged me with sad smiles.
استغربتُ من محاولة الجميع تشجيعي بابتسامات حزينة
I can't believe I learned of his lies only two weeks ago...
لا أصدّق أني سمعت بأكاذيبه قبل أسبوعين فحسب
I hastily negotiated with him, but he said there was no turning back
ذهبتُ لمناقشته هلعاً، لكنه قال أنّه أعلن سلفاً
as he had already announced this was the final Gomera movie.
أنّ هذا سيكون فيلم غوميرا الأخير، ولا عودة الآن
Everyone'll have long forgotten that rubber freak in a year!
!سينسى الجميع وحش المطّاط ذاك بعد سنة
Why didn't you talk with us?!
!لمَ لم تتكلم معنا؟
I couldn't.
لم أستطع
It was too hard after seeing everyone working hard one last time...
فقد كانت رؤية الجميع يجتهدون مرة أخيرة عصيبة عليّ
But I regret nothing. Now Gomera won't have a final death scene.
لكن ما أنا بنادم. فلن يكون هناك مشهد موت نهائيّ لغوميرا الآن
I only feel bad about making the children see that.
أتحسّر على جعل الأطفال يرون ما رأوه فحسب
Say, Tomomi-chan. Did you really see him in the suit from behind?
أخبرينا يا تومومي-تشان، هل رأيتِ ماتشان في بذلة غوميرا حقّاً؟
No, I didn't see anything. He disappeared so quickly.
كلا، لم أرَ شيئاً. فقد اختفى سريعاً
Then how...
...كيف إذاً
I could tell by his movements, without having to see inside.
أحمق، يمكنني أن أعرف من مجرد تحركاته دون الحاجة للنظر داخلاً
After all, he's been my partner for these past ten years.
فقد كان زميلي الذي عمل معي في العشرة أعوام الفائتة
When Teraoka-san tried to arrest Matsuyama-san,
عندما حاول تيراوكا-سان اعتقال ماتسوياما-سان
the gun went off!
أُطلق المسدّس
Was this an accident?!
أكانت هذه حادثة؟
There's one thing we kept from the media--
بالمناسبة، هناك ما أخفيناه عن الإعلام بشأن حادثة الأمس
we found three sets of fingerprints on the gun.
وجدنا 3 بصمات مختلفة على المسدّس
Who does the third set belong to?!
لمن هي البصمة الثالثة؟
If the gun's owner did as I think, then...
...إن كان مالك المسدّس هو من أشتبه به، إذاً
The 3rd Set of Fingerprints Murder Case
جريمة قتل البصمة الثالثة
On the next Conan--
في الحلقة القادمة من كونان
Next Conan's Hint:
تلميح الحلقة القادمة
Video Cassette Case.
حافظة شريط فيديو
Next episode's case is super unique.
!قضيّة الحلقة القادمة فريدة جدّاً
I'm so excited for next week.
!كم أتطلّع للأسبوع القادم